{
  "title": "1.3",
  "definitions": {
    "IMITATE": {
      "word": "IMITATE",
      "phonetic": "(im'-ÔøΩtAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to copy, follow the example of, try to be like </p><p>To IMITATE something is to try to be like it, to copy it. You can IMITATE a person or a thing. </p><p>“He tried to IMITATE the sound of a duck.” </p><p>“She wants to IMITATE the figure skaters she sees on television.” </p><p>An IMITATION is something that is a copy of something else. </p><p>“The building is an IMITATION of an ancient Greek temple.” </p><p>“He did a funny IMITATION of a man slipping on a banana peel.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: IMITATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "SQUIRM": {
      "word": "SQUIRM",
      "phonetic": "(skwerm)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to twist about, wiggle, wriggle </p><p>To SQUIRM means “to twist the body about,” to <i class=“def-ital\">wiggle</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">wriggle</i>. </p><p>“The baby SQUIRMED so much I almost dropped him.” </p><p>“He’s trying to SQUIRM through the cellar window.” </p><p>People often twist about when they feel uncomfortable or embarrassed, and SQUIRM is also used to express this sense. </p><p>“Try not to SQUIRM in your chair while I introduce you to my uncle.”</p>"
    },
    "SOCIABLE": {
      "word": "SOCIABLE",
      "phonetic": "(s0'-shÔøΩb:)I)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">friendly, liking company, companionable </p><p>SOCIABLE means “liking the company of other people,” <i class=“def-ital\">friendly</i>. A SOCIABLE person just naturally likes to be with other people, even if they are strangers. </p><p>“They are a SOCIABLE couple, always inviting friends over.” </p><p>“We played a SOCIABLE game of poker.” </p><p>“We always enjoy the company of SOCIABLE people.” </p><p>SOCIABLE is the opposite of hostile or unfriendly. You cannot, for example, have a SOCIABLE fight.</p>"
    },
    "ACHIEVE": {
      "word": "ACHIEVE",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩchEv')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to gain, accomplish, get </p><p>ACHIEVE means to gain or to get, often with some degree of difficulty. </p><p>“He ACHIEVED his goal of learning to walk again after he had been crippled.” </p><p>“She realized that it was necessary to study to ACHIEVE an A in math.” </p><p>“Most of us have to work hard to ACHIEVE any success.” </p><p>The noun from ACHIEVE is ACHIEVEMENT, which means an accomplishment. </p><p>“His greatest ACHIEVEMENT was to score the winning touchdown.” </p><p>“She is not content to get by on her previous ACHIEVEMENTS, but is always looking for new fields to conquer.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACHIEVEMENT, n.</p>"
    },
    "RESEMBLE": {
      "word": "RESEMBLE",
      "phonetic": "(ri-zem'-b:)I)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to be like, look like, act like </p><p>RESEMBLE means “to be like or look like” somebody or something. </p><p>“She RESEMBLES her mother, particularly around the eyes.” </p><p>“The twins don’t RESEMBLE each other at all.” </p><p>“The son RESEMBLES his father in his patience and good humor.” </p><p>The noun from RESEMBLE is RESEMBLANCE. </p><p>“The RESEMBLANCE between distant relatives is often remarkable.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RESEMBLANCE, n.</p>"
    },
    "SHELTER": {
      "word": "SHELTER",
      "phonetic": "(shel'-t:)r)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">protection, safety </p><p>SHELTER is used in two senses. First, it is a building or place that gives protection. </p><p>“After half an hour they reached the ski SHELTER.” </p><p>“We stood in the bus SHELTER to keep out of the strong wind.” </p><p>Second, SHELTER means protection itself. </p><p>“We tried to find SHELTER from the heavy rain.” </p><p>“The family sought SHELTER in their basement from the bombs.” </p><p>SHELTER is also used as a verb and means to protect. </p><p>“The doorway of the building SHELTERED us from the storm.” </p><p>“The beach umbrella SHELTERS us from the burning sun.”</p>"
    },
    "GRASP": {
      "word": "GRASP",
      "phonetic": "(grasp)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to take, take hold of, seize, clutch; to understand, comprehend To GRASP something is to take hold of it. </p><p>“He GRASPED the handlebars of his bicycle.” </p><p>“She GRASPED the cup firmly with both hands so that it wouldn’t fall.” GRASP is also used to mean “to take hold of mentally,” to <i class=“def-ital\">understand</i>. </p><p>“I fail to GRASP how your plan will help us.” </p><p>“It took a lot of explaining, but finally Jim seemed to GRASP the idea.”</p>"
    },
    "STUMBLE": {
      "word": "STUMBLE",
      "phonetic": "(stuhm'-bÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to trip, walk unsteadily, make a mistake </p><p>To STUMBLE is to trip and almost fall, often as the result of hitting something that is in your way. </p><p>“The hidden wire caused him to STUMBLE, but he managed to stay on his feet.” </p><p>To STUMBLE is also to walk along unsteadily, to stagger, as if you were about to fall at any second. </p><p>“The drunk STUMBLED along, barely able to stand up.” </p><p>In general use the word can also mean “to speak or act clumsily,” to blunder or founder. </p><p>“Johnny STUMBLED over every word as he tried to read the sentence.” </p><p>“We didn’t know anything about it, so we just STUMBLED along, doing the best we could.”</p>"
    },
    "SHATTER": {
      "word": "SHATTER",
      "phonetic": "(shat'-ÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to break SHATTER means “to break into small pieces.” </p><p>SHATTER is used in connection with glass or anything like glass that breaks easily. </p><p>“The bottle rolled off the table and SHATTERED on the floor.” </p><p>“The windshield SHATTERED when the car hit the tree.” </p><p>SHATTER can be used in a broader sense about health, hopes, dreams, nerves, and the like. </p><p>“His nerves were SHATTERED by the terrible battle.”</p>"
    },
    "STOOP": {
      "word": "STOOP",
      "phonetic": "(stUp)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to bend down, bow down, lower oneself </p><p>To STOOP is to bend down from the waist. </p><p>“Jim STOOPED over to pick up a dime on the floor.” </p><p>“He STOOPED so that he wouldn’t hit his head on the pipe.” </p><p>From this physical sense STOOP has come to mean “to do something that is beneath you” in terms of either rank or morals. </p><p>“How could you STOOP to telling such an awful lie?” </p><p>“Why did the famous actor STOOP to doing television commercials?”</p>"
    },
    "DOWNCAST": {
      "word": "DOWNCAST",
      "phonetic": "(down'-kast)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">depressed, sad, discouraged </p><p>The word cast in DOWNCAST means <i class=“def-ital\">throw</i>, and DOWNCAST was originally a verb which meant to <i class=“def-ital\">throw down</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">overthrow</i>. Now DOWNCAST is only used as an adjective to describe spirits or looks that are “thrown down” because something sad has happened. </p><p>“We tried to cheer him up because he seemed DOWNCAST.” </p><p>“You look so DOWNCAST. What’s wrong?” </p><p>“Bobby has a right to be DOWNCAST. His fumble cost us the game.” </p><p>“Almost everyone feels DOWNCAST on a gray, gloomy day.”</p>"
    },
    "SPROUT": {
      "word": "SPROUT",
      "phonetic": "(sprowt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to spring up, begin to grow, send out leaves or buds </p><p>To SPROUT means to <i class=“def-ital\">spring up</i>, to <i class=“def-ital\">begin to grow</i>. SPROUT is most often used about plants or other growing things, but it has also come to be used about anything that grows suddenly or quickly. </p><p>“Because of the sudden increase in population, new towns SPROUTED up almost overnight.” </p><p>“When he was fourteen his beard began to SPROUT.” </p><p>SPROUT can also mean “to cause to grow, to send out new leaves.” </p><p>“The tree SPROUTED new buds in the spring.” </p><p>Usage: SPROUT is often followed by <i class=“def-ital\">up</i>.</p>"
    },
    "APPROACH": {
      "word": "APPROACH",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩprOch')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to near, come near </p><p>APPROACH means to <i class=“def-ital\">come near</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">get near</i>. </p><p>“We all felt relieved as we watched him APPROACH us without tripping.” </p><p>“What is the right way to APPROACH the king’s throne?” </p><p>“She was APPROACHING the age to leave home.” </p><p>APPROACH is also a noun that means a <i class=“def-ital\">road</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">way</i> to something. When APPROACH is used to mean <i class=“def-ital\">way</i>, it can be used in either the sense of a <i class=“def-ital\">path</i> or a <i class=“def-ital\">method</i>. </p><p>“We’ll have to use another APPROACH (method) to get him to agree.” </p><p>“The APPROACH (path) to the highway was blocked by snow.”</p>"
    },
    "RECOVER": {
      "word": "RECOVER",
      "phonetic": "(ri-kuhv'-ÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to get back; to become well </p><p>To RECOVER something is to get or win it back.  </p><p>“She RECOVERED the ring she had lost.” </p><p>“They RECOVERED his shoe from the bottom of the pond.” </p><p>“You’ll never RECOVER all the money you have wasted.” </p><p>When a person RECOVERS <i class=“def-ital\">from</i> something, he gets better, becomes well. </p><p>“He RECOVERED from the sickness.” </p><p>“She is fully RECOVERED from her accident.” </p><p>RECOVERY (the noun) is the act of getting back or getting better. </p><p>“He was pleased by the quick RECOVERY of his lost wallet.” </p><p>“Her RECOVERY from the illness will take many months.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RECOVERY, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "ABBREVIATE": {
      "word": "ABBREVIATE",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbrE'-vE-At)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to shorten </p><p>To ABBREVIATE something is to make it shorter by leaving out parts. The word is used particularly when talking about the shortening of words and phrases. </p><p>“The words ‘United States of America’ are ABBREVIATED to “USA\". </p><p>“His name was Albert, but he ABBREVIATED it to Al in order to save space.” </p><p>ABBREVIATE can be used about other things as well. </p><p>“The mayor’s speech had to be ABBREVIATED because we ran out of time.” </p><p>The noun from ABBREVIATE is ABBREVIATION. </p><p>“Mr. is the ABBREVIATION for Mister.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ABBREVIATION, n.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "3",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He IMITATES my work.",
          "answers": [
            "looks at",
            "destroys",
            "laughs at",
            "copies",
            "uses"
          ],
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "copies"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Make them SQUIRM.",
          "answers": [
            "cry",
            "beg",
            "twist about",
            "jump",
            "straighten up"
          ],
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "twist about"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Extremely SOCIABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "friendly",
            "funny",
            "kind",
            "political"
          ],
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "friendly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ACHIEVE recognition.",
          "answers": [
            "gain",
            "lose",
            "hate",
            "hope for",
            "demand"
          ],
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "gain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You RESEMBLE him.",
          "answers": [
            "hate",
            "lie to",
            "meet",
            "are like",
            "live near"
          ],
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "are like"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Need some SHELTER.",
          "answers": [
            "heat",
            "rest",
            "protection",
            "excitement",
            "advice"
          ],
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "protection"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He GRASPED the plate.",
          "answers": [
            "dropped",
            "threw",
            "stole",
            "took hold of",
            "breathed onto"
          ],
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "took hold of"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We mustn't STUMBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "run",
            "jump",
            "complain",
            "trip",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "trip"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHATTER the window.",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "darken",
            "drop",
            "close",
            "fix"
          ],
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "break"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Why must we STOOP?",
          "answers": [
            "stand up",
            "lose",
            "change",
            "dig",
            "bend down"
          ],
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "bend down"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone seemed so DOWNCAST.",
          "answers": [
            "tired",
            "depressed",
            "uncomfortable",
            "hopeful",
            "steady"
          ],
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "depressed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to SPROUT.",
          "answers": [
            "spring up",
            "flow",
            "ripen",
            "slide",
            "fall off"
          ],
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "spring up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They APPROACHED the top.",
          "answers": [
            "found",
            "hit",
            "neared",
            "left",
            "missed"
          ],
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "neared"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOVER the money.",
          "answers": [
            "steal",
            "keep",
            "look for",
            "beg for",
            "get back"
          ],
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "get back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ABBREVIATE it.",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "quicken",
            "spell",
            "shorten",
            "lengthen"
          ],
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "shorten"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a parrot IMITATE the sound of human speech?",
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a baby SQUIRM if he didn't want to be held?",
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a person who is always looking for a fight very SOCIABLE?",
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most students ACHIEVE perfect grades on all their exams?",
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there any RESEMBLANCE between horses and donkeys?",
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people need SHELTER during a snowstorm?",
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you GRASP an idea?",
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a good ice skater STUMBLE a lot?",
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a light bulb SHATTER?",
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you standing when you STOOP?",
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person be DOWNCAST if his best friend moved away?",
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most trees SPROUT leaves in the fall?",
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you APPROACH something without reaching it?",
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people RECOVER from a cold?",
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Dr. an ABBREVIATION for doctor?",
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Mary tried to IMITATE her older sister in everything she did.",
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SQUIRMED with displeasure whenever someone called him by his real name.",
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We chatted SOCIABLY for a while over a cup of tea.",
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He received several awards for his ACHIEVEMENTS in science.",
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The crowd RESEMBLED to welcome the new mayor.",
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The tree didn't give us enough SHELTER from the rain, so we ran into the house.",
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He GRASPED the end of the rope and pulled it toward him.",
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The wounded man STUMBLED to the door of the hospital, where he fainted.",
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SHATTERED the boards together with nails so that they wouldn't move.",
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jane had to really STOOP to jump over the fence.",
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She looked at them with a DOWNCAST expression and said her parents wouldn't let her go.",
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Several weeds began to SPROUT up in the new lawn.",
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When they saw the big dog APPROACH them, they ran away as fast as they could.",
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were not allowed to keep the treasure they RECOVERED from the sunken ship.",
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Paul ABBREVIATED the rope in half with a knife.",
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "IMITATE",
          "answers": [
            "create",
            "act like",
            "copy"
          ],
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SQUIRM",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "twist",
            "wriggle"
          ],
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SOCIABLE",
          "answers": [
            "friendly",
            "unwelcome",
            "neighborly"
          ],
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACHIEVE",
          "answers": [
            "get",
            "reach",
            "give"
          ],
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESEMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "match",
            "compare",
            "differ"
          ],
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHELTER",
          "answers": [
            "safety",
            "beauty",
            "warmth"
          ],
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRASP",
          "answers": [
            "understand",
            "take",
            "hit"
          ],
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STUMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "trip",
            "bend",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHATTER",
          "answers": [
            "explode",
            "break",
            "rot"
          ],
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STOOP",
          "answers": [
            "bend",
            "spin",
            "sink"
          ],
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOWNCAST",
          "answers": [
            "unhappy",
            "miserable",
            "ill"
          ],
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPROUT",
          "answers": [
            "bud",
            "grow",
            "decrease"
          ],
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPROACH",
          "answers": [
            "way",
            "chance",
            "path"
          ],
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOVER",
          "answers": [
            "get back",
            "win back",
            "look back"
          ],
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABBREVIATE",
          "answers": [
            "age",
            "cut",
            "shorten"
          ],
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}